<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hashed</title><link>/hashed.io/</link><description>Recent content on Hashed</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Hashed</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/hashed.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hashed Summit 2021</title><link>/hashed.io/team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/team/</guid><description>After the long lockdown, we had our first company summit in Cancun. We wanted to get out of our houses and celebrate a year of learning and growth–hang out, talk about the plan for 2022, and have fun together. Little did we know the team activity would become a survival test. Everyone arrived at noon on Friday, checked into the hotel, and grabbed lunch while enjoying the sea views. After two hours of downtime, we headed to our company meeting.</description><content>&lt;p>After the long lockdown, we had our first company summit in Cancun. We wanted to get out of our houses and celebrate a year of learning and growth–hang out, talk about the plan for 2022, and have fun together. Little did we know the team activity would become a survival test.
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="/hashed.io/hashed.io/img/team/Arrival_hu97ae672127d7352301317f9891f30e57_13397404_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
Everyone arrived at noon on Friday, checked into the hotel, and grabbed lunch while enjoying the sea views. After two hours of downtime, we headed to our company meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the main reasons to get the team together was to recap a successful year and share plans for the next year. We gave an industry update and talked about doubling down on TLOS and Substrate, expanding our Node operations, and keeping an eye on the Bitcoin Lightning network. We also talked about the importance of quality, polish, and what it means to live up to our Elite Builder ethos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day we had our team activity: a paddleboard loop from Cancun’s Nichupte Lagoon to the Caribbean Sea. The lagoon waters were calm. We stopped by a quiet beach and took a refreshing swim. Someone was bitten by something and screamed hysterically (that someone might have been me).
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="/hashed.io/hashed.io/img/team/Activity_hu43c747951cdecadeabb377addec56c90_872125_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
To get to the sea, we had to go under a bridge large enough for boats to go through. This is when the weather started to change and, in an instant, we were paddling under heavy rain with the wind against us. This meant we had to frantically paddle on only one side to avoid being pushed over by the wind. The situation felt dangerous and our WFH bodies were in pain. The thought “If I die, no one knows about my tokens” crossed our minds. With renewed determination, we made it. We were sore, wet, and cold, but happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day we had surfing lessons and by noon everyone was on the way home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like most, I love not having to go to the office, but there is something very special about in-person time. We are a young team (using “we” generously with me). Most of our Engineers were hired during the pandemic–a generation for whom WFH is normal. But the experience of discussing exciting news in person, going for a swim, and enjoying the sun together can’t be replaced. Paraphrasing Seneca: Good things are better with friends to share them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="/hashed.io/hashed.io/img/team/team-1_hu28e2d306d0d276a7c676e50c2d804e44_2390725_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
&lt;!---
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="/hashed.io/hashed.io/img/team/team-5_huc391073c8f9f310c15163143648a8a02_2059817_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="/hashed.io/hashed.io/img/team/team-4_hu5ead2b3b447e14f635a1c254128ae7f8_1031943_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
---></content></item><item><title/><link>/hashed.io/projects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/projects/</guid><description>Experience Project Description Top 10 Global Bank Designed and built enterprise grade blockchain infrastructure for managing digital assets that will be traded between world-class financial institutions Hypha Multi-tenant DAO platform with support for flexible governance models, double-entry accounting classifications and reports. Compliant with Wyoming DAO LLC Act, DAO-to-DAO agreements, payroll, treasury, and more. BennyFi DeFi product with Premium Bond mechanics that leverage crypto yields to incentivize high return savings that don’t risk the principal.</description><content>&lt;h5 id="experience">Experience&lt;/h5>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Project&lt;/th>
&lt;th>Description&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Top 10 Global Bank&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Designed and built &lt;strong>enterprise grade blockchain infrastructure&lt;/strong> for managing digital assets that will be traded between world-class financial institutions&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Hypha&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Multi-tenant &lt;strong>DAO&lt;/strong> platform with support for flexible governance models, double-entry accounting classifications and reports. Compliant with Wyoming DAO LLC Act, DAO-to-DAO agreements, payroll, treasury, and more.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>BennyFi&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>DeFi&lt;/strong> product with Premium Bond mechanics that leverage crypto yields to incentivize high return savings that don’t risk the principal.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Diamond Standard&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Backed 1:1 by diamond clusters, &lt;strong>NFTs&lt;/strong> secured via NFC, and custom-made cabinet vaults for custodians. Enabling the trading of diamonds as a commodity.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Telos Kitchen&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Pioneer &lt;strong>block producer&lt;/strong> candidate on the Telos network. Focused building open-source developer utilities and re-usable application components.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Proxy Financial&lt;/td>
&lt;td>&lt;strong>On-chain applications for real estate Broker-Dealers&lt;/strong>, including key tools for selling new products, sourcing capital, and holistically managing a public funding offering.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Snyder &amp;amp; Kearny&lt;/td>
&lt;td>Develop a &lt;strong>due diligence analytics platform for publicly traded real estate funds&lt;/strong>: REITS, IF, and CEF. The proprietary algorithms use historical and Html parsed data of SEC public filings.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;h5 id="current-stack">Current Stack&lt;/h5>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Ethereum | Solana | Polkadot | Flow | EOSIO | Kusama | Wax&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></content></item><item><title>An underrated speech</title><link>/hashed.io/articles/article-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/articles/article-1/</guid><description/><content/></item><item><title>Hashed values series: on a multichain future</title><link>/hashed.io/articles/article-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/articles/article-3/</guid><description/><content/></item><item><title>Kitchen Lands tokenizes 35 acres of wyoming land</title><link>/hashed.io/articles/article-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/articles/article-2/</guid><description/><content/></item><item><title>Solana vs Polkadot</title><link>/hashed.io/articles/article-4/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/hashed.io/articles/article-4/</guid><description/><content/></item></channel></rss>