<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hashed</title><link>https://hashed.io/</link><description>Recent content on Hashed</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022 Hashed</copyright><atom:link href="https://hashed.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hashed Summit 2021</title><link>https://hashed.io/team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/team/</guid><description>After the long lockdown, we had our first company summit in Cancun. We wanted to get out of our houses and celebrate a year of learning and growth. Hang out, talk about the plan for 2022, and have fun together. Little did we know the team activity would become a survival test. Everyone arrived at noon on Friday, checked into the hotel, and grabbed lunch while enjoying the sea views.</description><content>&lt;p>After the long lockdown, we had our first company summit in Cancun. We wanted to get out of our houses and celebrate a year of learning and growth. Hang out, talk about the plan for 2022, and have fun together. Little did we know the team activity would become a survival test.
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://hashed.io/img/team/Arrival_hu97ae672127d7352301317f9891f30e57_13397404_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
Everyone arrived at noon on Friday, checked into the hotel, and grabbed lunch while enjoying the sea views. After two hours of downtime, we headed to our company meeting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the main reasons to get the team together was to recap a successful year and share plans for the next year. We gave an industry update and talked about doubling down on TLOS and Substrate, expanding our Node operations, and keeping an eye on the Bitcoin Lightning network. We also talked about the importance of quality, polish, and what it means to live up to our Elite Builder ethos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day we had our team activity: a paddleboard loop from Cancun’s Nichupte Lagoon to the Caribbean Sea. The lagoon waters were calm. We stopped by a quiet beach and took a refreshing swim. Someone was bitten by something and screamed hysterically (that someone might have been me).
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://hashed.io/img/team/Activity_hu43c747951cdecadeabb377addec56c90_872125_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
To get to the sea, we had to go under a bridge large enough for boats to go through. This is when the weather started to change and, in an instant, we were paddling under heavy rain with the wind against us. This meant we had to frantically paddle on only one side to avoid being pushed over by the wind. The situation felt dangerous and our WFH bodies were in pain. The thought “If I die, no one knows about my tokens” crossed our minds. With renewed determination, we made it. We were sore, wet, and cold, but happy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next day we had surfing lessons and by noon everyone was on the way home.
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://hashed.io/img/team/team-1_hu28e2d306d0d276a7c676e50c2d804e44_2390725_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
Like most, I love not having to go to the office, but there is something very special about in-person time. We are a young team (using “we” generously with me). Most of our Engineers were hired during the pandemic. A generation for whom WFH is normal. But the experience of discussing exciting news in person, going for a swim, and enjoying the sun together can’t be replaced. Good things are better with friends to share them.&lt;/p>
&lt;!---
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://hashed.io/img/team/team-5_huc391073c8f9f310c15163143648a8a02_2059817_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;img src="https://hashed.io/img/team/team-4_hu5ead2b3b447e14f635a1c254128ae7f8_1031943_2000x0_resize_q75_box.jpg" alt="Our team">
&lt;/p>
---></content></item><item><title>Digitalness: Part 2 of 3: Digitalness Primer</title><link>https://hashed.io/digitalness-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:36:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/digitalness-2/</guid><description>Digitalness Primer Authors: Max Gravitt and Sam Newbold
digitalness [ dij-i-tl-nis ] Noun. The recognition that a series of electrical or magnetic signals may have the same rights as the natural entities or objects they represent. The legal industry has recognized forms of manifested intent in a variety of ways. Think of corporate proxies, surrogacies, trusts and wills. Digitalness is just another way, another mechanism to capture the intent of a person.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="digitalness-primer">Digitalness Primer&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Authors: &lt;a href="https://github.com/3yekn">Max Gravitt&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://www.csglaw.com/index_y.cfm?t=3&amp;amp;A=19042&amp;amp;format=xml&amp;amp;p=16431&amp;amp;stylesheet=AttorneyBio_New">Sam Newbold&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>digitalness [ dij-i-tl-nis ]
Noun. The recognition that a series of electrical or magnetic signals may have the same rights as the natural entities or objects they represent.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The legal industry has recognized forms of manifested intent in a variety of ways. Think of corporate proxies, surrogacies, trusts and wills. Digitalness is just another way, another mechanism to capture the intent of a person. Like a shareholder proxy casting a vote on a shareholder’s behalf, or a will that outlines how property is to be disposed of, digitalness functions the same way.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="identity">Identity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first building block of digitalness is Identity. In their &lt;a href="https://www.wyoleg.gov/2021/Introduced/SF0039.pdf">Digital Identity Act&lt;/a>, the state of Wyoming defines digital identity in both a personal and organizational context. In both, the identity is the &lt;strong>“intangible digital representation of, by and for [the entity], over which [the entity] intentionally communicates or acts.”&lt;/strong> The types of parties included with this scope are natural persons and legal or commercial entities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The act simply states that &lt;strong>“acts taken through a digital identity are attributable to the [entity] if they were taken by the entity.”&lt;/strong> This is an easy concept to understand in the non-digital, or traditional legal world we all commonly use.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="authenticity">Authenticity&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Perhaps the more challenging concept to grasp with digitalness is authenticity, i.e. how do users of digitalness ensure that software programs used to promulgate real human intent do so accurately? This is achieved with blockchain. The Wyoming Digital Identity Act does not impose an explicit requirement for a blockchain, wallet, or cryptography. There is a mention of &lt;strong>“showing the efficacy of a security procedure”&lt;/strong>, but the breadth of allowed mechanisms seems to be purposeful to transcend various forms of key custody and ensure the Act is future proof.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digital Identity, as simple as it sounds, connects the dots between private keys, blockchain accounts, and the actions (state changes) that they perform on the shared data set.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="assets">Assets&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With the Digital Asset Act, Wyoming was the first state to define that digital asset &lt;strong>“means a representation of economic, proprietary or access rights that is stored in a computer readable format and is either a digital consumer asset, digital security or virtual currency.”&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This act mostly clarifies custodial regulations and practices for banks, respecting the reality that tokens or coins are in fact assets is a key component of digitalness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To summarize so far, on-chain actions taken by specific keys or accounts are the actual actions of the actors, and the on-chain state (e.g. token balances) and state changes (e.g. transfers) may involve actual assets. Pretty simple.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="decentralized-autonomous-organizations-dao-bill">Decentralized Autonomous Organizations (DAO) Bill&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Wyoming was the first State in the United States to introduce the Limited Liability Company (LLC) by &lt;a href="https://www.wyomingllcs.com/history-of-the-llc/">passing legislation in 1977&lt;/a>. An LLC is a business structure that limits any owners' personal responsibility for the company’s debts or liabilities. The LLC has been wildly popular for decades as an alternative to corporations, partnerships, and sole proprietorships because of the protective shield and favorable tax treatment by state and federal government.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://www.wyoleg.gov/2021/Introduced/SF0038.pdf">DAO Bill&lt;/a> is a supplement to the original Wyoming Limited Liability Company Act. It states that all of the provisions of LLCs apply to DAOs, and specifies the information required to establish a DAO in the state. Think of it as akin to non-profits or s-corps that are formed as corporations under the corporate laws of states but are treated differently based on certain operational and governance elections made at the time of formation and special tax filings made by the owner.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="requirements">Requirements&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>LLCs are suggested to have two documents:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Articles of Organization&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Operating Agreement&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>A DAO&amp;rsquo;s Articles of Organization (founding document) must have a statement that the company is a decentralized autonomous organization. This is similar to how corporations who wish to be treated as non-profit corporations must have a statement in the charter that the entity will operate as a non-profit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The LLC’s Articles of Organization for DAOs must have the following text:&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>NOTICE OF RESTRICTIONS ON DUTIES AND TRANSFERS
The rights of members in a decentralized autonomous organization may differ materially from the rights of members in other limited liability companies. The Wyoming Decentralized Autonomous Organization Supplement, underlying smart contracts, articles of organization and operating agreement, if applicable, of a decentralized autonomous organization may define, reduce or eliminate fiduciary duties and may restrict transfer of ownership interests, withdrawal or resignation from the decentralized autonomous organization, return of capital contributions and dissolution of the decentralized autonomous organization.
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>The registered name of the LLC must contain “DAO”, “LAO”, or “DAO LLC”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The articles of organization shall include a publicly available identifier of any smart contract directly used to manage, facilitate or operate the decentralized autonomous organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="smart-contract-requirements">Smart Contract Requirements&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The above items all pertain to content or information that must be in the registration. The Act also defines what decisions and duties the smart contract must govern. In the below sections, the numbered &lt;code>requirements&lt;/code> are quoted from the legislation, and the &lt;code>implementation&lt;/code> that follows is a description of how we have addressed it.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 1&lt;/code> Relations among the members and between the members and the decentralized autonomous organization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 1&lt;/code> The word “relations” seems a bit strange here, but there are no relations among the members besides what is defined in the smart contract. The contract’s action signatures (e.g. for creating proposals) are public and clear.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 2&lt;/code> Rights and duties under this chapter of a person in their capacity as a member&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 2&lt;/code> Members have a right to make proposals and vote on proposals. They also have the right to transfer their membership interests at any time, unless otherwise proposed and managed via an upgrade to the base contract (for activities such as staking).&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 3&lt;/code> Activities of the decentralized autonomous organization and the conduct of those activities&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 3&lt;/code> The DAO may elect, via a vote or proposal, to hire third parties or agents to conduct off-chain activities, such as paying taxes or fees. These parties or agents may or may not be members of the DAO.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 4&lt;/code> Means and conditions for amending the operating agreement&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 4&lt;/code> The operating agreement is maintained wholly on-chain. It can only be updated via a vote from members.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 5&lt;/code> Rights and voting rights of members&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 5&lt;/code> Membership interests are measured and maintained via a standard token contract, where the DAO itself is the issuer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This token is a unit of account.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Voting power is equivalent to membership interest. Both are calculated as the number of tokens owned by the voter divided by the total supply of that token.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 6&lt;/code> Transferability of membership interests&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 6&lt;/code> Transferability is instant and final based on transfer of the DAO’s token.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 7&lt;/code> Withdrawal of membership&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 7&lt;/code> A member may withdraw by transferring their membership interests to the DAO’s smart contract.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 8&lt;/code> Distributions to members prior to dissolution&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 8&lt;/code> Members are entitled to a share of all assets owned by the DAO, proportional to their membership interests in the DAO.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 9&lt;/code> Amendment of the articles of organization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 9&lt;/code> The operating agreement is maintained wholly on-chain. It can only be updated from a vote from members.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 10&lt;/code> Procedures for amending, updating, editing or changing applicable smart contracts&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 10&lt;/code> The operating agreement is maintained wholly on-chain. It can only be updated from a vote from members.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Req 11&lt;/code> All other aspects of the decentralized autonomous organization&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Impl 11&lt;/code> From time to time, there may be off-chain activities required by the DAO, such as placing an offer on a property or paying property taxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>These are handled via an elected agent of the DAO, who may or may not be a member.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="code-is-law">Code is Law&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>One of the Act’s most &lt;strong>&lt;em>consequential and empowering&lt;/em>&lt;/strong> aspect is found in the &lt;strong>Miscellaneous&lt;/strong> section:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Where the underlying articles of organization and operating agreement are in conflict, the articles of organization shall preempt any conflicting provisions. Where the underlying articles of organization and smart contract are in conflict, the smart contract shall preempt any conflicting provisions of the articles of organization.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>This establishes a hierarchy of power or precedence among the core documents of a DAO LLC. The Articles of Organization trump the Operating Agreement, and the Smart Contract trumps the Articles of Organization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;code>Smart Contract &amp;gt; Articles of Organization &amp;gt; Operating Agreement&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;mdash;-&lt;em>The smart contract is the most powerful of all&lt;/em>&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; &lt;strong>CODE IS LAW&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This clause clarifies that the on-chain smart contract is the highest, most trusted source of information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This clarification empowers the machine code above all else, which is a critical factor in allowing digitalness to thrive.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This makes sense in a classic legal manner because the smart contract is the best proxy, or best clue for understanding the intent of the parties. It is an explicit understanding that forcing smart contract machine code to comply with paper documents or written words unravels its value proposition. If it were even cryptographically possible, the ability for a government judicial body to overrule the machine code would create an existential vulnerability for any DAO.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In other words, the on-chain records represent &lt;strong>instant and final settlement of state-protected property rights.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="future-of-digitalness">Future of Digitalness&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Wyoming’s legislation on Digital Identity, Assets, and Organizations are a substantial enabler of innovation in our space. It establishes the start of a framework for how people, businesses, and property may be handled on blockchain networks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our mission is to continue to push the boundaries of open innovation by developing products that accelerate adoption of digitalness around the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-1">Digitalness: Part 1 of 3 - An Underrated Speech&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-3">Digitalness: Part 3 of 3 - Step by Step DAO Proof of Concept&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Digitalness: Part 3 of 3: Kitchen Lands DAO LLC buys 35 acres in Wyoming</title><link>https://hashed.io/digitalness-3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 10:36:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/digitalness-3/</guid><description>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC buys 35 acres in Wyoming Author: Max Gravitt
In the prior article, we shared the breakdown of our understanding of Wyoming&amp;rsquo;s new Digitalness legislation.
I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share that we have implemented them in a real-world proof of concept. We created a new business: Kitchen Lands DAO LLC, and that DAO purchased 35 beautiful acres outside of Laramie, Wyoming.
We took a methodical approach to the activities described below.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="kitchen-lands-dao-llc-buys-35-acres-in-wyoming">Kitchen Lands DAO LLC buys 35 acres in Wyoming&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Author: &lt;a href="https://github.com/3yekn">Max Gravitt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the prior article, we shared the breakdown of our understanding of &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-2/">Wyoming&amp;rsquo;s new Digitalness legislation&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share that we have implemented them in a real-world proof of concept. We created a new business: &lt;strong>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC&lt;/strong>, and that DAO purchased 35 beautiful acres outside of Laramie, Wyoming.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We took a methodical approach to the activities described below. Our goal to ensure that the DAO was decentralized and transparent from genesis. This article explains the play-by-play.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-1-genesis-member-key-ceremony">Step 1. Genesis member key ceremony&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Every DAO starts as an idea, usually from a single person, before it is born. This single person usually recruits additional founding members. Although not required, we held a key ceremony with the founding members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another common genesis event is likely a crowdfunding contract, where contributions codify the members and genesis tokenization.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-2-create-an-account">Step 2. Create an account&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="https://eosauthority.com/account/landdao.tk?network=telos#keys">blockchain account&lt;/a> was created and configured for multisignature based on the founding members.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This may also be achieved using the fully sovereign, direct democracy permission from the start, meaning the only permission on the blockchain account would be the &lt;code>landdao.tk@eosio.code&lt;/code> permission. Since the number of genesis members was small, we elected for multisignature for simplicity.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-3-deploy-contract">Step 3. Deploy contract&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>We use a &lt;a href="https://hashed-io.github.io/document-graph-book/">document-graph smart contract&lt;/a> to serve as a flexible and powerful store for DAO information. This allows us to store any arbitrary key value pairs, DAO policies, documentation, files, images, videos, and so on in a format that is easy to access and update via governance rules.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-4-register-the-dao-llc">Step 4. Register the DAO LLC&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The DAO LLC must be registered by an organizer, who may or may not be a member of the DAO. The organizer of Kitchen Lands DAO LLC was Telos Kitchen DAO LLC, a block producer on Telos.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As mentioned in our prior article, there is a set of information required specifically for DAO LLCs. Here is our Additional Article with this information.&lt;/p>
&lt;pre>&lt;code>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC is a decentralized autonomous organization.
The smart contract is deployed to the Telos blockchain.
Telos Website: https://telos.net
ChainID: 4667b205c6838ef70ff7988f6e8257e8be0e1284a2f59699054a018f743b1d11
Smart Contract (operating agreement) Deployment: landdao.tk
Smart Contract web-link: https://telos.bloks.io/account/landdao.tk
Source code repo: https://github.com/teloskitchen/land-dao
Restrictions on Duties and Transfers appears in the smart contract operating agreement
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;p>At this point, our LLC is registered and has been filed with the Wyoming Secretary of State. The document is publicly available online and has a section indicated that it has been filed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It also includes a Certificate of Organization signed by the Secretary of State of Wyoming.
&lt;img src="registration-annotated.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-5-enable-memberships">Step 5. Enable Memberships&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Act requires that the public smart contract identifier be referenced in the Articles of Organization, and some members may not want to join a DAO that doesn’t have the proper LLC registration. This is why we adhere to the sequence of: a) create the account, b) deploy the contract, c) register the DAO LLC, and then d) allow members to join.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Members joined Kitchen Lands DAO LLC by sending TLOS tokens to the &lt;code>landdao.tk&lt;/code> contract. (enrollment is closed; do not send any tokens)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can &lt;a href="https://eosauthority.com/transaction/4199fcbab0c8a932b52057c534b140df0f66a295e1d6cb9a7dce9692e5492d74?network=telos#">view the transaction on the block explorer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-6-distribute-initial-dao-tokens">Step 6. Distribute initial DAO tokens&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC elected to create a distribute token with the following configuration:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Symbol: &lt;code>LAND&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Precision: 0 (no decimal places)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Maximum Quantity: 100&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This means each &lt;code>LAND&lt;/code> token is equivalent to 1% of the DAO and the smallest fractional ownership of the DAO is 1%,&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At this point, the DAO received contributions of &lt;code>50,000.0000 TLOS&lt;/code> from three members, in proportions of 45%, 45%, and 10%.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-7-go-shopping">Step 7. Go Shopping!&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>After much research, the DAO members decided on a 35 acre property just northwest of Laramie in the Laramie River Ranch community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="property-cover-image.jpg" alt="">
&lt;a href="https://horizonlandsales.com/property/laramie-river-ranch-lot-45-35-84-acres/">See full property details&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To avoid the slowness and hassle of fiat, we made our offer in Bitcoin and the seller was happy to accept it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We made an offer at the list price with the conversion rate of USD to Bitcoin to be made at the time of the transactions. Of course, the buyer is Kitchen Lands DAO LLC.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="purchase-agreement.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-8-title-insurance">Step 8. Title Insurance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Title insurance is an optional step, but generally regarded as a best practice when purchasing real estate. The hired insurance company investigates the property to make sure that there are no outstanding liens, judgments, or back taxes. If it later becomes evident that there were some judgments or liens against the property, the insurance company will guarantee or fix it up to the purchase amount.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC is the insurance policy holder, as seen in the below policy snippet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="title-insurance.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-9-settlement">Step 9. Settlement&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>At this point, the funds can be transferred to the seller and the property deeded to the DAO. Many real estate transactions involve the use of an escrow agent. The price of bitcoin escrow services is very high (10% of the escrow amount). Because of this cost, along with the relationship we had established with the seller and the size of the transaction, the DAO voted and elected not to use an escrow agent.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, two events occurred simultaneously:
The seller signed, had notarized, and emailed the Deed that grants the property to Kitchen Lands DAO LLC.
&lt;img src="deed.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Kitchen Lands DAO LLC sent the Bitcoin to the seller.
&lt;img src="btc-trx-electrum.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.blockchain.com/btc/tx/72caecac4fa2028d8dfd1e822238db8bc405a1a30e60a545a24bbed20897eecc">Open on block explorer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-10-file-the-original-deed-with-the-albany-county-clerk">Step 10. File the Original Deed with the Albany County Clerk&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The final step of the transaction, which is often handled by an escrow agent, is to file the signed deed in the county where the property is located. Across the USA, counties are responsible for knowing which entities own each real property in that county. Among other reasons, this is required because property tax falls to the jurisdiction of counties and they need to know who to send the bill to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="tax-page.png" alt="">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://maps.greenwoodmap.com/albany/map#zcr=17.00366750385988/-11764707.2/5138229.5/0&amp;amp;lyrs=publand,townlim,ownership,roads">County Property Detail Page&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="step-11-ongoing-maintenance">Step 11. Ongoing Maintenance&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>There are some ongoing maintenance activities associated with owning real estate and also keeping LLC records current. These duties and costs are shown below.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;a href="https://itax.tylertech.com/AlbanyWY/detail.aspx?taxid=16394">Annual Property taxes&lt;/a>: &lt;code>$129.87&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Community dues: &lt;code>$120.00&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Wyoming LLC fee: &lt;code>$60.00&lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There would be obviously consequences for not performing these maintenance activities, including loss of the property itself. Kitchen Lands DAO LLC maintains an on-chain reserve to cover these for years to come, and a member or hired agent will be responsible for handling the transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If an existing reserve ran out, a DAO could issue more tokens in exchange for contributors replenishing the reserve. Like any LLC, the DAO members are incentivized to ensure these obligations get paid.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>If you made it this far, thank you for learning about our DAO LLC proof of concept with Kitchen Lands DAO LLC. If you appreciate this work, please vote for Telos Kitchen as block producer on the Telos blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-1/">Digitalness: Part 1 of 3 - An Underrated Speech&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-2">Digitalness: Part 2 of 3 - Digitalness Primer&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title/><link>https://hashed.io/assets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/assets/</guid><description>Assets Logos Click to Download Click to Download Png Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Avatar Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Symbol Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Halftone Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download Click to Download</description><content>&lt;h1 id="assets">Assets&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="logos">Logos&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="grid">
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/jpg/logo-black.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/jpg/logo-black.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/jpg/logo-green-blue.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/jpg/logo-green-blue.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h3 id="png">Png&lt;/h3>
&lt;div class="grid">
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/png/logo-black.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/png/logo-black.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/png/logo-green-blue.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/png/logo-green-blue.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/png/logo-gradient-white.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/png/logo-gradient-white.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/png/logo-black.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/png/logo-black.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/png/logo-white-blue.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/png/logo-white-blue.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="avatar">Avatar&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="grid">
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/avatar/black-white.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/avatar/black-white.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/avatar/gradient.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/avatar/gradient.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/avatar/green-white.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/avatar/green-white.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="symbol">Symbol&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="grid">
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/symbol/black.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/symbol/black.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/symbol/gradient.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/symbol/gradient.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/symbol/green.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/symbol/green.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/symbol/white.png" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/symbol/white.png">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div>
&lt;h2 id="halftone">Halftone&lt;/h2>
&lt;div class="grid">
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/circular.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/circular.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/earth.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/earth.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/eye.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/eye.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/grid.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/grid.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/lines.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/lines.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure>
&lt;img src="images/halftone/pattern.jpg" alt="">
&lt;figcaption>&lt;a download href="images/halftone/pattern.jpg">Click to Download&lt;/a>&lt;/figcaption>
&lt;/figure>
&lt;/div></content></item><item><title>Digitalness Part 1 of 3: An Underrated Speech</title><link>https://hashed.io/digitalness-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/digitalness-1/</guid><description>An Underrated Speech Author: Max Gravitt
On June 30, 2000, just six months after our harrowing survival of Y2K, President Bill Clinton signed into law the Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act. His speech took place in Congress Hall in Philadelphia, where Congress ratified the United States Bill of Rights in 1791.
President Clinton&amp;rsquo;s speech is especially salient for our times.
It is inspiring and features a live presidential demo that erupts to thundering applause.</description><content>&lt;h2 id="an-underrated-speech">An Underrated Speech&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Author: &lt;a href="https://github.com/3yekn">Max Gravitt&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On June 30, 2000, just six months after our harrowing survival of Y2K, President Bill Clinton signed into law the &lt;a href="https://uscode.house.gov/view.xhtml?req=granuleid%3AUSC-prelim-title15-chapter96&amp;amp;saved=%7CZ3JhbnVsZWlkOlVTQy1wcmVsaW0tdGl0bGUxNS1zZWN0aW9uNzAwMQ%3D%3D%7C%7C%7C0%7Cfalse%7Cprelim&amp;amp;edition=prelim">Electronic Signatures in Global and National Commerce Act&lt;/a>. His speech took place in Congress Hall in Philadelphia, where Congress ratified the United States Bill of Rights in 1791.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="congress-hall.png" alt="congress-hall">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>President Clinton&amp;rsquo;s speech is especially salient for our times.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is inspiring and features a live presidential demo that erupts to thundering applause. The president provided a compelling glimpse into the possibilities of the innovation of the time. The speech is a reminder of our current challenge - the unfortunate absence of national or executive branch leadership on modern Digitalness.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Watch the 12 minute speech below, he starts with:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Two hundred and thirteen years ago, about 100 feet from where we are now, in a summer as hot as this one, the Founding Fathers drafted the Constitution of the United States.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/tZhqpl0nsOU" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>In the very first article of that document, they wrote that, government shall make no laws, &amp;lsquo;impairing the obligation of contracts.&amp;rsquo; James Madison called the contract clause &amp;ndash; and I quote again &amp;ndash; &amp;lsquo;a constitutional bulwark in favor of personal security and private rights.&amp;rsquo; He and his fellow framers understood that the right of individuals to enter into commercial contracts was fundamental not just for economic growth, but for the preservation of liberty itself.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>He later shares his easy to understand, fair principles that served as guidance for the legislation.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We said that the rules should be simple and nonregulatory, that they should not favor one technology over another, and they should give individuals and organizations maximum freedom to form electronic contracts as they see fit. I&amp;rsquo;m grateful that Congress has kept those principles in mind as it drafted the Electronic Signatures Act.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Twenty-one years later, the mentions of bipartisanship and common future sound foreign. He mentioned that there was&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>… a new vision of government and politics that marries our most enduring values to the demands of the new Information Age. In many ways, the Electronic Signatures Act exemplifies that vision. It shows what we in Washington can accomplish when we put progress above partisanship, when we reach across party lines to work for the American people and our common future.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The demonstration reminds us that this was six years before the launch of the iPhone, and smartphones of course became more ubiquitous than the e-card used in the demonstration. President Clinton finishes with a look ahead&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>And all of you young people will someday look back on this day that you were here and marvel that we thought it was any big deal. And that will be the ultimate test of success.&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="digitalness">Digitalness&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://www.wyoleg.gov/Committees/2022/S19">Wyoming’s Select Committee on Blockchain, Financial Technology and Digital Innovation Technology&lt;/a> has architected 25 bills on Digitalness that have been enacted into law. The purpose of this legislation, as &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/rothfuss">Senator Rothfuss&lt;/a> expressed during a session last year, is &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;to enable, not to restrict.&amp;quot;&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digitalness clarity is a new mechanism for digital attestation like the Electronic Signature Act 20 years ago; it establishes a holistic framework for digital identity, assets, and organizations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Digitalness empowers people to govern shared goals and assets at an unprecedented speed, durability, and adaptability. This breakthrough innovation will drive economic innovation throughout the 21st century.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This Digitalness legislation is broader in scope and scale, yet is cut from the same cloth as the Electronic Signatures Act. At their core, they both serve to &lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;marr[y] our most enduring values to the demands of the new [Digitalness] Age&amp;hellip; for the preservation of liberty itself&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-2">Digitalness: Part 2 of 3 - Digitalness Primer&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://hashed.io/digitalness-3">Digitalness: Part 3 of 3 - Step by Step DAO Proof of Concept&lt;/a>&lt;/p></content></item><item><title>Document Graph</title><link>https://hashed.io/dge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/dge/</guid><description>Introduction Document Graph is a flexible persistence and modeling framework for blockchain applications.
Use Cases Document Graph is currently used for a number of use cases. Here are some real-world examples that we are using it for. Interestingly, all of the below use cases can be handled within the same graph where nodes can be linked to each other across contexts.
DAOs DAOs have have descriptive attributes. They also have members, proposals, assignments, quests, bounties, badges, and many other data types that are maintained to support a fully functional platform.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Document Graph is a flexible persistence and modeling framework for blockchain applications.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="use-cases">Use Cases&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Document Graph is currently used for a number of use cases. Here are some real-world examples that we are using it for. Interestingly, all of the below use cases can be handled within the same graph where nodes can be linked to each other across contexts.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="daos">DAOs&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>DAOs have have descriptive attributes. They also have members, proposals, assignments, quests, bounties, badges, and many other data types that are maintained to support a fully functional platform.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s an actual example of how Document Graph is used to manage a few components within a DAO&amp;rsquo;s information space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="graph-example.png" alt="Example Graph">&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="supply-chain">Supply Chain&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We use Document Graph for a supply chain traceability application. An &lt;code>Item&lt;/code> and its various &lt;code>Checkpoints&lt;/code> are saved as &lt;code>documents&lt;/code>. When a new QR code &lt;code>scan&lt;/code> event occurs, it extends the graph for that item to contain a new &lt;code>Checkpoint&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since a &lt;code>Checkpoint&lt;/code> is a document, it can store any arbitrary data that describes that event, such as weight, longitude, latitude, cost, and even photos or other files such as packing lists. Files are stored in IPFS and anchored into the on-chain document.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Users have the option to save data directly onto the chain (for access within smart contracts) or to save the data to IPFS. Users also have the option to encrypt the data with a password of their choice.&lt;/p>
&lt;img id="plantuml-eg"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-eg");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ndigraph G {\n rankdir=LR;\n Item -\u003e Checkpoint_1 [label=\u0022scan\u0022];\n Item -\u003e Checkpoint_2 [label=\u0022scan\u0022];\n Item -\u003e Checkpoint_3 [label=\u0022scan\u0022];\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="accounting">Accounting&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>We also use the Document Graph to store data required to operate a double-entry accounting system. This system allows users to generate classical accounting reports such as Balance Sheet and Income Statement from blockchain transactions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Accountants must be able to tag transactions with additional data, references, files, etc., and they must also be able to assign a general ledger account to appropriately calculate debits and credits.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="features">Features&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="end-user-accessibility">End-user Accessibility&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The Document Graph Explorer allows for any user with a blockchain account to create and edit content that they own within the graph, and they may create between any two nodes in the graph.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This level of accessibility to non-technical users is unprecedented. It allows them to collaboratively create and connect content with all of the benefits of blockchain. This level of capability was previously only accessible to highly technical engineers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="file-and-ipfs-integration">File and IPFS Integration&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Document Graph has integrated support for storing data or files within IPFS and saving that files’ CID (hash) within the document.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="encryption-support">Encryption Support&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Document Graph Explorer supports encryption of a specific content item’s value. In DGE, the user is prompted to enter a password that is used for symmetric AES encryption. This secret simply encrypts the value and the ciphertext is persisted in the document.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In a future release, we may integrate with the &lt;a href="https://phala.network/en/">Khala/Phala&lt;/a> confidential blockchain. Also, we are evaluating integration with &lt;a href="https://www.pad.tech/">PAD&lt;/a> as a trustless way to share the secret in a manner that alerts the owner when the secret is accessed. This is useful for interesting use cases such as one-time decrypt use cases and “in case of emergency” use cases.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="graphql-caching">GraphQL Caching&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Document Graph supports easy integration with &lt;a href="https://dgraph.io">DGraph&lt;/a>, an open source distributed graph engine. The document graph cache listens for new blocks, and upon finalization, updates the DGraph graph to reflect any updates to the on-chain graph. DGraph has excellent tooling and ergonomics for querying, custom types or schemas, data visualizer, full-text search, and much more.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="composable-sdk-experience-cli">Composable SDK Experience (CLI)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Document Graph is built to be highly composable and also support an ergonomic developer experience. In addition to the Document Graph Explorer web application, there is a CLI (written in Go) that supports all of the create, read, update, and delete operations directly against the blockchain.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="plugin-architecture-for-custom-renderers-and-editors">Plugin Architecture for Custom Renderers and Editors&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Developers can include special fields within their document to enable custom viewers or editors. For example, if the field “preferred_renderer” or “preferred_editor” is populated with an endpoint, this endpoint will be used to render or edit the document.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="background-of-semantic-triples">Background of Semantic Triples&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Databases typically store data in a tabular format, where a table has set of columns and rows, like a spreadsheet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, IRL, we tend to think in statements of &lt;code>Subject&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Predicate&lt;/code> (&lt;code>Verb&lt;/code>), and &lt;code>Object&lt;/code>. This is particularly true in the English language where word order is subject, verb, object (SVO). This information construct is known as &lt;code>triples&lt;/code>, or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Semantic_triple">semantic triples&lt;/a>. The &lt;a href="https://www.w3.org/RDF/">W3C Resource Description Framework&lt;/a> is a leading specification for organizing these statements into semantic triples.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As Lenhert describes &lt;a href="https://www.synaptica.com/triples-triads-and-semantics/">here&lt;/a>:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;One of the fundamental benefits of these RDF-based controlled vocabulary structures are their dual nature as being both human intelligible as well as machine readable (and, therefore, portable). Like their basic constituent subject-verb-object basis, ontologies convey rich meaning in relatively simple and compact statements, making them extremely useful in modeling complex knowledge environments.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>The following diagrams express semantic triples in various terms.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="using-the-natural-english-sovhttpsenwikipediaorgwikisubjecte28093verbe28093object-terms">Using the natural English &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Subject%E2%80%93verb%E2%80%93object">SOV&lt;/a> terms&lt;/h3>
&lt;img id="plantuml-dg1"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-dg1");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ndigraph G {\n rankdir=LR;\n Subject -\u003e Object [label=\u0022Verb\u0022];\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;h3 id="using-common-graph-theoryhttpsenwikipediaorgwikivertex_graph_theory-terms">Using common &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertex_(graph_theory)">graph theory&lt;/a> terms&lt;/h3>
&lt;img id="plantuml-dg2"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-dg2");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ndigraph G {\n rankdir=LR;\n Vertex1 -\u003e Vertex2 [label=\u0022Edge\u0022];\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;h3 id="using-the-document-graph-terms">Using the Document Graph terms&lt;/h3>
&lt;img id="plantuml-dg3"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-dg3");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ndigraph G {\n rankdir=LR;\n Document1 -\u003e Document2 [label=\u0022Edge\u0022];\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Note that edges are both directional and labeled.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="simple-example-of-a-semantic-triple">Simple Example of a Semantic Triple&lt;/h3>
&lt;img id="plantuml-dg4"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-dg4");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ndigraph G {\n rankdir=LR;\n Document1 -\u003e Document2 [label=\u0022Edge\u0022];\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="blockchain-change-management">Blockchain Change Management&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>At their core, blockchains are used to manage data and state changes on that data. The structure of this data is nearly always based on a custom-built struct within a pallet or smart contract. Applications that are built on blockchains are typically built for a specific smart contract’s data structure, and the application is highly coupled to that application. When a data structure changes, it typically requires a complex migration of existing data and source code within the smart contract as well as perhaps changes to other backend or service layers and the application itself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, assume the overly simplified struct within a smart contract. Upon an approval, the amount would be sent to the account indicated.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-rust" data-lang="rust">&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">struct&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Proposal&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> label: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">str&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> account: &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">AccountId&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> amount: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">u32&lt;/span>,
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Then, let&amp;rsquo;s say the DAO wants to add support for recurring payments. This would need to be supported within the data model by adding a time period to use as the recurring period and the total number of payments.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-rust" data-lang="rust">&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">struct&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">Proposal&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> title: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">str&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> account: &lt;span style="color:#a6e22e">AccountId&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> amount: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">u32&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> time_period_seconds: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">u32&lt;/span>,
&lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">pub&lt;/span> payment_count: &lt;span style="color:#66d9ef">u32&lt;/span>,
}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Depending on the blockchain, this change management event requires a series of gymnastics by developers to maintain a reasonable user experience. For example, on non-upgradable platforms, it may require clients to query from both structs, or if upgradable, may require erasing data from the original data store and recreating it (losing metadata in the process). Some may require maintaining both structures and adding a roll-up of sorts to maintain client backwards compatibility.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All of these complications create a significant change management burden on software developers.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="document-graph-solves-this">Document Graph Solves This&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Document Graph alleviates the need for developers to change their persistence layer when making upgrades to their data model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is achieved by supporting flexible variant pairs within a consistently structured &lt;code>document&lt;/code> type and support for an &lt;code>edge&lt;/code> type used to link the graph&amp;rsquo;s documents in meaningful ways.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="specification">Specification&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="document-data-model">Document Data Model&lt;/h2>
&lt;img id="plantuml-dg5"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-dg5");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\n@startmindmap\n* Document\n** Header\n*** Hash\n*** Owner\n*** Type\n*** Created \u0026 Updated Dates\n** Content Group 1\n*** Content Item 1\n**** Key (label)\n**** Value\n*** Content Item n\n** Content Group n\n@endmindmap\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;p>Each document is comprised of the following:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Header
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>[required] creator (account)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[required] graph contract (where the document is saved)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[optional] created date (timepoint)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[optional] updated date (timepoint)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>[optional] hash of content (not including certificates or header)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Value (variant) = &lt;code>std::variant &amp;lt;asset, string, time_point, name, int64&amp;gt; &lt;/code>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content = an optionally labeled FlexValue&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content Group = vector&lt;Content>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Content Groups = vector&lt;ContentGroup>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Each document contains a single instance of ContentGroups.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>This provides enough flexibility to support:
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>data of all supported types,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>short clauses of annotated text,&lt;/li>
&lt;li>longer form sequenced data, e.g. chapters.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Certificates [optional]
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Each document has &lt;code>O..n&lt;/code> certificates.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Certificate
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>certifier: the &amp;lsquo;signer&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li>
&lt;li>notes: string data provided by signer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>certification_date: time_point&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></content></item><item><title>Hashed Chain - Chaos</title><link>https://hashed.io/hashed-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hashed.io/hashed-chain/</guid><description>Introduction Hashed Chain supports many of the popular prebuilt pallets, listed below, and also a custom pallet for Fruniques (FRactional UNIQUES) and a custom pallet for a gated marketplace, supporting optional pre-approval of each asset and each participant a configured set of Origin.
One immediate use case is with one of our partners, a tax credit marketplace. Tax credits are non-fungible tokens that may be subdivided in a manner where all data is inherited except for the amount, which is subtracted from the parent (similar to a UTXO chain).</description><content>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://github.com/hashed-io/hashed-substrate/">Hashed Chain&lt;/a> supports many of the popular prebuilt pallets, listed below, and also a custom pallet for &lt;code>Fruniques&lt;/code> (&lt;code>FR&lt;/code>actional &lt;code>UNIQUES&lt;/code>) and a custom pallet for a gated marketplace, supporting optional pre-approval of each asset and each participant a configured set of Origin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One immediate use case is with one of our partners, a tax credit marketplace. Tax credits are non-fungible tokens that may be subdivided in a manner where all data is inherited except for the amount, which is subtracted from the parent (similar to a &lt;a href="https://academy.glassnode.com/concepts/utxo">UTXO chain&lt;/a>). This process may repeat indefinitely.&lt;/p>
&lt;table>
&lt;thead>
&lt;tr>
&lt;th>Frunique Specifications&lt;/th>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/thead>
&lt;tbody>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>A &lt;code>Frunique&lt;/code> is a type of NFT.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>Like a vault, any set of fungible tokens or &lt;code>NFTs&lt;/code> may be locked into a &lt;code>Frunique&lt;/code>. The locked assets may only be unlocked when the &lt;code>Frunique&lt;/code> is burned.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Fruniques&lt;/code> can be composed of other &lt;code>Fruniques&lt;/code>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Fruniques&lt;/code> support minting a new &lt;strong>fungible&lt;/strong> token that is backed by a &lt;code>Frunique&lt;/code>.&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;tr>
&lt;td>&lt;code>Fruniques&lt;/code> support &lt;a href="https://github.com/paritytech/substrate/tree/master/frame/uniques">Uniques&lt;/a> and &lt;a href="https://github.com/paritytech/substrate/tree/master/frame/assets">Assets&lt;/a> specifications for interoperability&lt;/td>
&lt;/tr>
&lt;/tbody>
&lt;/table>
&lt;p>This &lt;code>gated marketplace&lt;/code> includes a role for &lt;code>enroller&lt;/code> that is reponsible for confirming that new participants in the marketplace are eligible to participate. The accounts that hold &lt;code>enrollers&lt;/code> status are decided by the marketplace creator, and may be dynamic based on any Origin.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>An &lt;code>asset enroller&lt;/code> role may be responsible for confirming that new assets in the marketplace are eligible to participate. In the case of tax credits, a licensed CPA attests to the authenticity based on the information provided.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The marketplace may also include a role for &lt;code>asset burner&lt;/code> or redeemer, which may be responsible for working with participants to offboard their assets. This may involve having a licensed CPA or attorney send information or a form with various parties, or perhaps have a deed notarized. The specific asset will govern which asset burners are eligible.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="open-hashed-chain-on-polkadotjsorghttpspolkadotjsorgappsrpcwss3a2f2fn1hashedsystemsexplorer">&lt;a href="https://polkadot.js.org/apps/?rpc=wss%3A%2F%2Fn1.hashed.systems#/explorer">Open Hashed Chain on polkadot.js.org&lt;/a>&lt;/h3>
&lt;h2 id="architecture">Architecture&lt;/h2>
&lt;img id="plantuml-hc1"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-hc1");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\nnode \u0022Other Polkadot Ecosystem\u0022 as OPE {\n [Other Marketplaces]\n}\n\npackage \u0022Protocol Layer\/Hashed Chain\u0022 {\n [Fruniques Pallet]\n [Marketplace Pallet] --\u003e [Other Marketplaces]\n [Advanced Frunique UI\/UX]\n [Services and Caching]\n}\n\nnode \u0022Statemint Chain\u0022 as SC {\n [Uniques Pallet]\n [Fruniques Pallet] --\u003e [Uniques Pallet]\n [Fruniques Pallet] --\u003e [Assets Pallet]\n [Assets Pallet]\n [Assets Pallet] --\u003e [Other Marketplaces]\n}\n\npackage \u0022End User Experiences\u0022 {\n [Afloat\/Tax Credits] --\u003e [Fruniques Pallet]\n [Afloat\/Tax Credits] --\u003e [Services and Caching]\n [DAO LLC Registrations] --\u003e [Fruniques Pallet]\n [DAO LLC Registrations] --\u003e [Services and Caching]\n [\u0027Get Gifted\u0027 NFTs] --\u003e [Fruniques Pallet]\n [Marketplace UI\/UX] --\u003e [Fruniques Pallet]\n [Marketplace UI\/UX] --\u003e [Marketplace Pallet]\n [\u0027Get Gifted\u0027 NFTs] --\u003e [Marketplace UI\/UX]\n}\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;h2 id="composability">Composability&lt;/h2>
&lt;img id="plantuml-hc2"/>
&lt;script src="https://hashed.io/js/rawdeflate.js">&lt;/script>
&lt;script>
function encode64(data) {
r = "";
for (i=0; i&lt;data.length; i+=3) {
if (i+2==data.length) {
r +=append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1), 0);
} else if (i+1==data.length) {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), 0, 0);
} else {
r += append3bytes(data.charCodeAt(i), data.charCodeAt(i+1),
data.charCodeAt(i+2));
}
}
return r;
}
function append3bytes(b1, b2, b3) {
c1 = b1 >> 2;
c2 = ((b1 &amp; 0x3) &lt;&lt; 4) | (b2 >> 4);
c3 = ((b2 &amp; 0xF) &lt;&lt; 2) | (b3 >> 6);
c4 = b3 &amp; 0x3F;
r = "";
r += encode6bit(c1 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c2 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c3 &amp; 0x3F);
r += encode6bit(c4 &amp; 0x3F);
return r;
}
function encode6bit(b) {
if (b &lt; 10) {
return String.fromCharCode(48 + b);
}
b -= 10;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(65 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b &lt; 26) {
return String.fromCharCode(97 + b);
}
b -= 26;
if (b == 0) {
return '-';
}
if (b == 1) {
return '_';
}
return '?';
}
var deflater = window.SharedWorker &amp;&amp; new SharedWorker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
if (deflater) {
deflater.port.addEventListener('message', done_deflating, false);
deflater.port.start();
} else if (window.Worker) {
deflater = new Worker('/js/rawdeflate.js');
deflater.onmessage = done_deflating;
}
function done_deflating(e) {
const img = document.getElementById("plantuml-hc2");
img.src = "http://www.plantuml.com/plantuml/img/"+encode64(e.data);
}
function compress(s) {
s = unescape(encodeURIComponent(s));
if (deflater) {
if (deflater.port &amp;&amp; deflater.port.postMessage) {
deflater.port.postMessage(s);
} else {
deflater.postMessage(s);
}
} else {
setTimeout(function() {
done_deflating({ data: deflate(s) });
}, 100);
}
}
compress("\n@startuml\ntitle \u0022Fruniques Composability\u0022\nnode \u0022Statemine NFT A\u0022 as statemine_nft_a\nnode \u0022Statemine NFT B\u0022 as statemine_nft_b\n\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT 1\u0022 as frq_1\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT 2\u0022 as frq_2\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT n\u0022 as frq_n\n\nnode \u0022Fungible Token\u0022 as fung_1\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT 2.1\u0022 as frq_2_1\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT 2.2\u0022 as frq_2_2\nnode \u0022Frunique NFT 2.3\u0022 as frq_2_3\n\nnote left of frq_2\n Source NFT locked and 1..n new Fruniques \n can be minted.\nend note\n\nnote bottom of frq_2_1\n Metadata values are inherited by\n default unless overridden.\nend note\n\nnote bottom of fung_1\n Parent Frunique owner decides \n the token supply, symbol, and \n metadata and is minted the tokens\nend note\n\nstatemine_nft_a --\u003e frq_1 \nstatemine_nft_b --\u003e frq_2 \nstatemine_nft_b --\u003e frq_n\n\nfrq_1 --\u003e fung_1\n\nfrq_2 --\u003e frq_2_1\nfrq_2 --\u003e frq_2_2\nfrq_2 --\u003e frq_2_3\n@enduml")
&lt;/script>
&lt;p>For more information about Fruniques, see the &lt;a href="https://github.com/hashed-io/hashed-substrate/tree/main/pallets/fruniques">pallet documentation&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="other-pallets-on-hashed-chain">Other Pallets on Hashed Chain&lt;/h3>
&lt;h4 id="identityhttpswikipolkadotnetworkdocslearn-identity">&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/learn-identity">Identity&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>Hashed Chain provides a naming system that allows participants to add information, such as social media accounts, web domains, email addresses, etc. to their on-chain account and subsequently ask for verification of this information by registrars.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="indiceshttpswikipolkadotnetworkdocslearn-accountsindices">&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/learn-accounts#indices">Indices&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>An index is a short and easy-to-remember version of an address. Claiming an index requires a deposit that is released when the index is cleared.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="social-recovery">&lt;a href="">Social Recovery&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Recovery pallet is an M-of-N social recovery tool for users to gain access to their accounts if the private key or other authentication mechanism is lost. Through this pallet, a user is able to make calls on-behalf-of another account which they have recovered. The recovery process is protected by trusted &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; whom the original account owner chooses. A threshold (M) out of N friends are needed to give another account access to the recoverable account.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="uniques-nftshttpsgithubcomparitytechsubstratetreemasterframeuniques">&lt;a href="https://github.com/paritytech/substrate/tree/master/frame/uniques">Uniques (NFTs)&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>A simple, secure module for dealing with non-fungible assets.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="treasuryhttpswikipolkadotnetworkdocslearn-treasury">&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/learn-treasury">Treasury&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Treasury pallet provides a &amp;ldquo;pot&amp;rdquo; of funds that can be managed by stakeholders in the system and a structure for making spending proposals from this pot.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Roadmap: Integrate support for native multisig BTC in the treasury via PSBT and output descriptors&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="societyhttpswikipolkadotnetworkdocsmaintain-guides-society-kusama">&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/maintain-guides-society-kusama">Society&lt;/a>&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>The Society module is an economic game which incentivizes users to participate and maintain a membership society.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="bountieshttpswikipolkadotnetworkdocslearn-treasurybounties-spending">&lt;a href="https://wiki.polkadot.network/docs/learn-treasury#bounties-spending">Bounties&lt;/a>&lt;/h4></content></item></channel></rss>